hello and welcome to the 16th tutorial
on how to program descriptive
so in this tutorial i'm going to show
you about weapons
so let's open the
rc i'm going to use the out game rc
because i can add my the weapons to
myself with the player list
so let's click the stored icon and we
can see all our weapons let's click add
weapon
and add it and call it
awesome
sit
script
and we can see an icon for it and let's
add some code
function on weapon fired
this is a new function i'm going to show
you what it does is as soon as you
select the weapon
in your inventory script it's not here
right now but as soon as you select it
then press d it's going to run the
script
not all weapons are going to have this
so you can't activate them by pressing d
after selecting them you're going to
have to activate them in some other way
if you even do activate them some
weapons are running constantly like the
movement script or a chat system like
those weapons are running constantly
with loops
so anyway
let's add some code set any
sit
no
set any is a client side command
but
everybody in the
entire server can't see you as you sit
down
but only you sit down like no one else
sits down so anyway i'm going to apply
and we're going to go to
player list
right click myself press edit attributes
then go to weapons
then add it
they add the script awesome
sit
script
click apply
now if i press q you'll see the weapon
right there
this is the icon for the weapon
it defaults to bc alarm clock
if you do if you create the weapon with
in-game rc
you're gonna have to add the icon
through
the outgame mercy so if i take this out
it's not going to show an icon
you can also add your own icons through
from the images folder in rc
like go here
then press the little plus next to the
levels folder and you can see all your
images you can add whatever you want
so anyway
let's see i want to change the script
and make it go
on
created
now what's going to happen
oh i forgot the parentheses
as soon as i press apply
i'm going to automatically sit down
because in a weapon on created means as
soon as the player enters the level
enters the server or as soon as the
weapon is updated or added to the player
so if i
go out i can move around
then i press apply
i'm going to sit down
we can also do on
player chats
and go if
player.chat is equal to
sit
and click apply now as soon as i say sit
i'm going to sit down
if i press q the script will be there
but if i press d nothing's going to
happen so you may wondering it's pretty
useless to even have this here because
if you click it and press d nothing's
going to happen
well we can also we can make it so it's
not shown here but it'll still be on the
player
to do that let's make a new weapon
and call it
sit two
oh i forgot one thing daryl knife that's
lame at minus sign
sit two
you have to have the minus sign there
okay
then we're going to copy the code
click apply
then i'm going to add it to myself
oh yeah and for this awesome script i'm
just gonna take away
i'm just gonna delete it
no there
so now
uh
i'm going to delete it from here
now the weapon the original weapon is
gone as you can see we don't have any
weapon here that's gonna make us sit
down
but when we press when we type sit
we're gonna sit down wanna know because
the weapon
sit two
has the minus sign in front that means
the weapon is added to us you know if
it's even added
but we won't see it here
so it's a great way to make like huds or
inventory scripts where you don't want
it to be shown here
so if i do something if i change on
player chats to on weapon fired
there will be no way to even activate
the
script because there's no way to select
it and then press d
so anyway that can